Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the Socialist Party (U.S.) PE.032
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the Socialist Party (U.S.)
1901-2002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
PE.032
13 Linear Feet (13 boxes)
The collection consists of leaflets, flyers, manifestoes, reports, memoranda, executive committee minutes, pamphlets, a ledger and other internal documents generated by the Socialist Party of America. Also included are related organizations such as Socialist Democratic Federation, Young People's Socialist League and Socialist Party USA. The collection offers a general feel for the types of printed matter put out by the Party as well as a brief introduction to and history of the Party and how it changed over the years.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged into six series:
I. Socialist Party of America: National Office, 1901-1961 II. Socialisty Party of America: States and Local, 1902-1981, undated III. Socialist Party U.S.A., 1962-1992 IV. Related Socialist Organizations, 1957-1972 V. Young People's Socialist League (YPSL), 1916-2002 VI. Election Campaign Handbooks, 1908-1937
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Scope and Content Note
This artifical collection, created over the years by staff of Tamiment via donations, personal collectiong and materials removed from other collections, consists of memoranda, correspondence, constitutions, fliers, leaflets, newspaper clippings, and pamphlets. The collection offers a general feel for the types of printed matter put out by the Party as well as a brief introduction to and history of the Party and how it changed over the years. Represented in the collection are the Sociality Party of America (Socialist Party (U.S.), the later Socialist Party U.S.A., the Young People's Socialist League (YPSL) and a few other related organizations.
The bulk of the collection consists of papers, fliers, pamphlets and other party material from the Socialist Party of America headquartered in Chicago. Another significant portion of the collection comes from the Socialist Party of New York City. Also included are materials from Young People's Socialist Party (YPSL), an organization of young socialists. There are election campaign handbooks from the National Headquarters as well as some state and county affiliates. The Party went through several splits and in 1973, the Socialist Party of the USA was formed, which is the organization today.
Some of the oldest items in the collection come from individual states party papers, such as Kansas, Kentucky, Maryland, New Jersey, Pennsylvania and Wisconsin. The Young People's Socialist League contains significant information on the conventions, education and communications in this group.
A ledger added to collection in 2018 documents membership dues and contributions from the Socialist Party of America's local division in Granite Falls, Washington. The ledger contains a short index followed by numerous pages filled with members' names and other details; each entry displays information pertaining to their occupation, age, date of admittance and payment records. Notable names in the ledger include E.E. Martin and R. Krueger, secretaries of state for the Socialist party in 1905 and 1907, respectively, as well as prominent Socialist party member and anti-war activist Emil Herman, who is listed in the ledger as a speaker on 27 January 1908. Entries range from 1901 to 1913.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Socialist Party (U.S.) Correspondence TAM 056.9 (R-7124)
Socialist Party of New York State Records TAM 056.4 (R-7124)
Socialist Party (U.S.) Minutes TAM 056.6 (R-7124)
Socialist Minute Books (New York, N.Y.) TAM 056.1 (R-7124)
Historical Note
The Socialist Party of America was established on 29 July 1901 as a result of a merger between the moderate wing of the Socialist Labor Party and the Social Democratic Party. For most of its turbulent history, the Socialist Party has been reformist in its political attitudes and democratic in its organization. Until the mid 1950s, the Socialist Party advocated trade unionism, supported an evolutionary rather than a revolutionary conversion to socialism, and endorsed progressive as well as socialist candidates for public office.
Between 1901 and 1912, the party's membership grew from 10,000 to 118,000 and the votes cast for socialist Presidential candidates increased proportionately from 100,000 to 900,000. By advocating reform of the political and economic system, the party was able to enlist the support of many orthodox socialists and many heterogeneous elements remaining from such progressive movements as the Greenbackers, Populists, and "Single Taxers". The result was a broad based party, particularly strong in the West, which was prepared to sacrifice ideological purity for numbers and revolutionary gains for immediate political success. Evidence of this policy was demonstrated in the fact that in 1912 there were 56 socialist mayors, over 300 socialist aldermen, many socialist state legislators, and one socialist member of the House of Representatives.
This success, however, was short lived. Throughout the 1910s and 1920s, the Socialist Party suffered from the same external pressures which caused other progressive movements to stagnate. The party also suffered from numerous internal crises as well, including the expulsion of its revolutionary wing in 1912 1913; the party's official opposition to World War I, and the Russian Revolution of 1917, which encouraged the left wing of the party to demand a more militant program and, when this was not forthcoming, to secede from the party in 1919 and establish the Communist Party.
Following a brief resurgence in the late 1920s and early 1930s under the strong leadership of Norman Thomas, the Socialist Party was once again plagued with internal conflicts. The principal divisions within the party at this time were generational, geographical, and ideological in nature.
These three factions did not bring their differences of opinion into public focus until the 1932 Socialist Party convention in Milwaukee. The conflict intensified during the New York City fur workers dispute in 1933. In the fur industry of New York City there were two rival unions, one controlled by the Socialist Party Old Guard and the other led by the Communist Party. During the dispute over which union should represent all of the fur workers, the Militants charged that the Old Guard was attempting to subvert the communist union in its quest for total control despite the fact that most of the workers supported the communists. Norman Thomas concurred in this view and demanded that the Old Guard cease its activities against the communist union members. The Old Guard union responded to these charges by obtaining a labor injunction against the communist union. Eventually, the fur workers dispute was resolved when members of both unions negotiated a settlement.
Another incident which pitted the three factions against each other occurred during the debate on the Declaration of Principles at the 1934 Socialist Party convention in Detroit. The Declaration of Principles was drafted by the Progressives and the Militants and included numerous statements on issues which they believed every socialist should advocate. When the delegates finally adopted the Declaration of Principles before the convention adjourned, it clearly demonstrated that the Old Guard was gradually losing control of the party.
The factional strife came to a climax in 1936 when the Old Guard bolted from the Socialist Party after the national convention in Cleveland and organized the Social Democratic Federation. The withdrawal of the Old Guard was a serious loss for the party. Not only did major socialist figures from New York, Connecticut, Maryland, and Pennsylvania leave the party, but they took with them much of the financial support of the party as well. In addition to these developments, two major urban political machines in the Socialist Party Reading, Pennsylvania and Bridgeport, Connecticut joined the Social Democratic Federation.
Following the departure of the old Guard, the Progressives and militants continued the party's infighting by dividing into three groups. The first group was an amalgamation of the old Progressives and the leadership of the Militants. Under the direction of Jack Altman and Paul Porter these moderates supported the American Labor Party and endorsed a more democratic view of socialism. A second group, formerly associated with the Militants, were emerging as the new left wing faction of the party. Calling itself the "Clarity" group after the periodical, Socialist Clarity, this group was led by Frank Trager, Gus Tyler, Robert and Max Delson, and Herbert Zam. Ideologically, the Clarity group was not opposed to labor parties and farm labor coalitions, but they were more insistent than the Altman group that any labor party wanting Socialist Party support should have a wide labor base and should repudiate capitalist reformist politics.
Complicating the situation within the party was an ultra left Trotskyite faction. Known as the Appeal group because of their periodical, Socialist Appeal, the Trotskyites maintained that the Socialist Party should repudiate all labor and farmer labor parties and thus transform itself into a revolutionary party.
These three factions clashed on a variety of issues during the late 1930s. In national convention sessions and local political campaigns, these groups differed over the Socialist Party's attitude toward preventing war, the Socialist Party's affiliation with the American League Against War and Fascism, and socialist cooperation with organized labor. By the end of 1937, the disputes between the various groups were so damaging to the conduct of party business that the National Executive Committee finally took decisive action and expelled the Trotskyite faction.
The Socialist Party never fully recovered from these setbacks, although negotiations were successful in reuniting the Social Democratic Federation with the party in 1957. Nevertheless, despite this encouraging development, the internal conflicts and the emergence of the New Left in the late 1950s and 1960s eventually caused the Socialist Party to lose its influence as an effective political organization.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this collection have been compiled by the Tamiment Library.
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives purchased a ledger from the Socialist Party (U.S.) in March 2018. The accession number associated with this purchase is 2018.075.
Materials found in the repository were added to the collection. The accession number associated wiht this material is 2014.091.
Clippings (information artifacts); Socialists -- New York (State) -- New York.; Socialism -- New York (State).; Morningside Heights (New York, N.Y.); Chicago (Ill.); Fliers (printed matter); New York (N.Y.); Pamphlets.; Socialism -- United States.; Correspondence.; Ledgers (account books).; Socialist Party (U.S.); Young People's Socialist League
- Series I. Socialist Party (U.S.): National Office (also called Socialist Party of America), 1901-1961; 294676
  - 1901-1903, 294674 (Box 1)
  - 1904, 294675 (Box 1)
  - 1905, 294678 (Box 1)
  - 1906, 294679 (Box 1)
  - 1907: National Headquarters Weekly Bulletin, 294680 (Box 1)
  - 1908, 294681 (Box 1)
  - 1909, 294682 (Box 1)
  - 1910, 294683 (Box 1)
  - 1911, 294684 (Box 1)
  - 1912 I, 294685 (Box 1)
  - 1912 II, 294686 (Box 1)
  - 1913, 294687 (Box 1)
  - 1914: National Committee Session, 294688 (Box 1)
  - 1914: Socialist War Manual, 295246 (Box 1)
  - 1915: National Committee Session, 294689 (Box 1)
  - 1916, 294690 (Box 1)
  - 1917, 294691 (Box 1)
  - 1918, 294692 (Box 1)
  - 1919: National Convention, 294693 (Box 1)
  - 1919-1920: National Executive Committee, 294694 (Box 1)
  - 1919-1920, 294695 (Box 1)
  - 1920: National Executive Committee, 294696 (Box 1)
  - 1920-1930: Fliers and Circular Letters, 294697 (Box 1)
  - 1921, 294698 (Box 1)
  - 1922, 294699 (Box 1)
  - 1923: National Convention, 294700 (Box 1)
  - 1924, 294701 (Box 1)
  - 1925, 294702 (Box 1)
  - 1926, 294703 (Box 1)
  - 1927, 295069 (Box 2)
  - 1928 I, 295070 (Box 2)
  - 1928 II, 295071 (Box 2)
  - 1928: National Election Results, 295072 (Box 2)
  - 1929, 295073 (Box 2)
  - 1930 I, 295074 (Box 2)
  - 1930 II, 295075 (Box 2)
  - 1931 I, 295076 (Box 2)
  - 1931 II, 295077 (Box 2)
  - 1932 I, 295078 (Box 2)
  - 1932 II, 295079 (Box 2)
  - 1932: Newspaper Clippings, 295080 (Box 2)
  - 1933 I, 295081 (Box 2)
  - 1933 II, 295082 (Box 2)
  - 1934 I, 295083 (Box 3)
  - 1934 II, 295084 (Box 3)
  - 1934 III, 295085 (Box 3)
  - 1934 IV, 295086 (Box 3)
  - 1935 I, 295087 (Box 3)
  - 1935 II, 295088 (Box 3)
  - 1936 I, 295089 (Box 3)
  - 1936 II, 295090 (Box 3)
  - 1936 III, 295091 (Box 3)
  - 1936: Election, 295092 (Box 3)
  - 1937, 295093 (Box 3)
  - 1938, 295094 (Box 3)
  - 1939, 295095 (Box 3)
  - 1940, 295110 (Box 4)
  - 1940: Election, 295111 (Box 4)
  - 1940-1949: Internal Debate, 295112 (Box 4)
  - 1941, 295113 (Box 4)
  - 1942, 295114 (Box 4)
  - 1943, 295115 (Box 4)
  - 1944, 295116 (Box 4)
  - 1945, 295117 (Box 4)
  - 1946, 295118 (Box 4)
  - 1947, 295119 (Box 4)
  - 1948, 295120 (Box 4)
  - 1949, 295121 (Box 4)
  - 1950, 295122 (Box 4)
  - 1951, 295123 (Box 4)
  - 1952, 295124 (Box 4)
  - 1953, 295125 (Box 4)
  - 1954, 295126 (Box 4)
  - 1955, 295127 (Box 4)
  - 1956, 295128 (Box 4)
  - 1957 I, 295129 (Box 4)
  - 1957 II, 295130 (Box 4)
  - 1957 III, 295131 (Box 4)
  - 1958 I, 295132 (Box 4)
  - 1958 II, 295133 (Box 4)
  - 1959, 295134 (Box 4)
  - 1960, 295135 (Box 5)
  - 1961, 295136 (Box 5)
  - undated, 295247 (Box 5)
  - Education, undated; 295248 (Box 5)
  - Election Statistics, undated; 377537 (Box 5)
  - Fliers, 1913, undated; 295249 (Box 5)
  - Fliers I, undated; 295137 (Box 5)
  - Fliers II, undated; 295250 (Box 5)
  - Fliers/Circular Letters, circa 1919, undated; 295138 (Box 5)
  - German Language Federation, circa 1900s; 295251 (Box 5)
  - Independent Political Council, undated; 346687 (Box 5)
  - Lyceum Department, 1912; 295252 (Box 5)
  - Memoranda and Minutes, undated; 295139 (Box 5)
  - Memoranda, Correspondence, undated; 295140 (Box 5)
  - National Executive Committee, undated; 295253 (Box 5)
  - Norman Thomas Testimonial Committee, 1936, 1950; 295141 (Box 5)
  - Pamphlets and Publications I, 1911-; 295254 (Box 5)
  - Pamphlets and Publications II, 300822 (Box 5)
  - Pamphlets and Publications III, 300823 (Box 5)
  - Pamphlets and Publications IV, 300824 (Box 5)
  - Pamphlets and Publications V, 300825 (Box 5)
  - Polish Alliance, undated; 295326 (Box 5)
  - Revolutionary Policy Committee, 1934; 295327 (Box 5)
  - Woman's National Committee, undated; 295255 (Box 5)
  - Women's Department, 1930; 295348 (Box 5)
- Series II. Socialist Party of America: State and Local, 1902-1981, undated; 295109
  - Arizona, 1910-1914; 295143 (Box 5)
  - Arkansas, 1922, undated; 295144 (Box 5)
  - California, 1912-1960, undated; 295145 (Box 5)
  - Colorado, 1913-1944, undated; 295146 (Box 6)
  - Connecticut, 1912-1943; 295147 (Box 6)
  - Cook County, IL, 1931-1937, undated; 295148 (Box 6)
  - Delaware, 1913-1919; 295149 (Box 6)
  - District of Columbia (D.C.), 1914-1937; 295150 (Box 6)
  - Florida, 1910-1912; 295151 (Box 6)
  - Idaho, 1914, undated; 295152 (Box 6)
  - Illinois, 1907-1973; 295153 (Box 6)
  - Indiana, 1914-1934; 295154 (Box 6)
  - Indiana and Illinois, 1940s; 295155 (Box 6)
  - Iowa, 1914, undated; 295156 (Box 6)
  - Kansas, 1903; 295157 (Box 6)
  - Kentucky, 1903, undated; 295158 (Box 6)
  - Louisiana, 1931; 295159 (Box 6)
  - Maine, 1914; 295160 (Box 6)
  - Maryland, 1904-1906, undated; 295161 (Box 6)
  - Massachusetts, 1910-1944; 295162 (Box 6)
  - Michigan, 1907-1934; 295163 (Box 6)
  - Minnesota, 1916-1936, undated; 295164 (Box 6)
  - Mississippi, 1913; 295165 (Box 6)
  - Missouri, 1904-1934; 295166 (Box 6)
  - Montana, 1912; 295167 (Box 6)
  - Nebraska, 1910; 295168 (Box 6)
  - Nevada, 1913-; 295169 (Box 6)
  - New Hampshire, undated; 295170 (Box 6)
  - New Jersey, 1902-1939; 295171 (Box 6)
  - New Jersey, undated; 295172 (Box 6)
  - New Mexico, 191-; 295173 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1904, 295174 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1905, 295175 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1906, 295176 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1907, 295177 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1908, 295178 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1909, 295179 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1910, 295180 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1911, 295181 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1912, 295182 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1913, 295183 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1914-1916, 295184 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1917, 295185 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1918, 295186 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1919, 295187 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1920, 295188 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1921, 295189 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1922, 295190 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1924, 295191 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1925, 295192 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1926, 295240 (Box 6)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1927-1928, 295241 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1929, 295242 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1930, 295243 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1931, 295244 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1932, 295245 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1933, 295256 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1934, 1934-1938; 295193 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1934: National Executive Committee, 295194 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1935, 295195 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1936, 295196 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1937, 295197 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1938, 295198 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1939, 295199 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1940, 295200 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1946-1947 I, 295201 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1946-1947 II, 295202 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1948-1949, 295203 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1950-1951, 295204 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1952-1953, 295205 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1954-1955, 295206 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1956, 295207 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1957, 295208 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1958, 295209 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1964-1965, 295210 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1968, 295211 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): 1969, 295212 (Box 7)
  - New York (N.Y.): undated, 295213 (Box 8)
  - New York (N.Y.): undated, 295214 (Box 8)
  - New York (N.Y.): East Side Agitation Committee, 1917; 295215 (Box 8)
  - New York (N.Y.): Left-wing Section, 1919, 1936; 295257 (Box 8)
  - New York (N.Y.): Morningside Heights I (The Bulletin), 1940; 295216 (Box 8)
  - New York (N.Y.): Morningside Heights II (The Bulletin), 1940; 295217 (Box 8)
  - New York 1913, 295218 (Box 8)
  - New York 1914, 295219 (Box 8)
  - New York 1915, 295220 (Box 8)
  - New York 1916, 295221 (Box 8)
  - New York 1917, 295222 (Box 8)
  - New York 1918, 295223 (Box 8)
  - New York 1940-1949, undated, 295224 (Box 8)
  - New York: undated, 295239 (Box 8)
  - New York: Albany Trial, 1920; 295225 (Box 8)
  - New York: Candidates/Platform, 1919-1920; 295226 (Box 8)
  - New York: Candidates/Platform, 1926-1928; 295227 (Box 8)
  - New York: Candidates/Platform, 1930; 295228 (Box 8)
  - New York: Candidates/Platform, 1931-1933; 295229 (Box 8)
  - New York: Candidates/Platform, 1934-1938; 295230 (Box 8)
  - New York: Constitution/Convention, 1936; 295231 (Box 8)
  - New York: Fliers, 1930-1958; 295232 (Box 8)
  - New York: Left-Wing Section, Buffalo, NY, 1924; 295233 (Box 8)
  - New York: Memoranda, 1936-1937; 295234 (Box 8)
  - New York: Memoranda, 1973-; 295235 (Box 8)
  - New York: Split, 1937; 295236 (Box 8)
  - New York: State Committee- Memoranda and Minutes, 1937-1956; 295237 (Box 8)
  - New York: State Committee- Response to National Executive Committee, 1935; 295238 (Box 8)
  - New York: Young People's Socialist Federation, 1910- undated; 301897 (Box 8)
  - New York: Erie County, 1936; 295258 (Box 8)
  - New York, Schenectady, 1912; 295259 (Box 8)
  - North Dakota, 1914; 295260 (Box 8)
  - Ohio, 1905-1960; 295261 (Box 8)
  - Ohio: Cleveland, 1913, 1929; 295262 (Box 8)
  - Oklahoma, 1914-1915; 295263 (Box 8)
  - Oregon, undated; 295264 (Box 8)
  - Pennsylvania, 1903-1918; 295265 (Box 9)
  - Pennsylvania, 1919-1950, undated; 295266 (Box 9)
  - Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, 1910, 1964; 295267 (Box 9)
  - Rhode Island, Providence, 1914, 1920; 295268 (Box 9)
  - South Carolina, undated; 295270 (Box 9)
  - South Dakota, 1914; 295271 (Box 9)
  - Tennessee, 1912; 295272 (Box 9)
  - Texas, 1910-1934; 295273 (Box 9)
  - Texas, 1979-1980; 295311 (Box 9)
  - Texas, 1981-; 295312 (Box 9)
  - Texas, Tyler, Local 39, 1904; 295313 (Box 9)
  - Utah, 1908, 1934; 295314 (Box 9)
  - Virginia, 1930; 295315 (Box 9)
  - Washington: Financial Secretary's Ledger, 1901-1913 (Box 13)
  - Washington, 1912-1924; 295316 (Box 9)
  - Washington, 1960 -; 295317 (Box 9)
  - West Virginia, 1912; 295318 (Box 9)
  - Wisconsin, 1905-1934; 295319 (Box 9)
  - Wisconsin, 1936-1940; 295320 (Box 9)
  - Wisconsin, 1945-1960; 295321 (Box 9)
  - Wisconsin, 1961-1971; 295322 (Box 9)
  - Wisconsin, 1972-1973; 295323 (Box 9)
  - Wisconsin: Milwaukee, 1908-1932; 295324 (Box 9)
  - Wisconsin: Milwaukee County, 1934-1965; 295325 (Box 9)
- Series III. Socialist Party U.S.A., 1962-1992; 295328
  - 1962, 295329 (Box 9)
  - 1963, 295330 (Box 9)
  - 1964, 295331 (Box 9)
  - 1966, 295332 (Box 9)
  - 1968-1969, 295333 (Box 9)
  - 1970-1971 I, 295334 (Box 10)
  - 1970-1971 II, 295939 (Box 10)
  - 1972-1975, 295335 (Box 10)
  - 1976-1978, 295336 (Box 10)
  - 1980, 295337 (Box 10)
  - 1981-1993, 295338 (Box 10)
  - undated, 295339 (Box 10)
  - Committee on Perspectives, 1975; 295341 (Box 10)
  - Debs Caucus, 1971; 295342 (Box 10)
  - New York, 2002-2007, undated; 295340 (Box 10)
  - Northern New Jersey Socialist Party, circa 2009; 442520 (Box 10)
- Series IV. Related Socialist Organizations, 1957-1972; 295343
  - Social Democratic Federation, 1957-1960; 295344 (Box 10)
  - Democratic Socialist Federation, 1960-1972; 295345 (Box 10)
  - Democratic Socialist Federation: East Bay, Berkeley, California, 1960; 295346 (Box 10)
  - Baltimore Socialist Youth Forum, 1962; 300363 (Box 10)
- Series V. Young People's Socialist League (YPSL), 1916-2002; 295347
  - 1916-1917, 295349 (Box 10)
  - 1921-1926, 295350 (Box 10)
  - 1927-1928, 295351 (Box 10)
  - 1929, 295352 (Box 10)
  - 1930, 295353 (Box 10)
  - 1931, 295354 (Box 10)
  - 1932, 295355 (Box 10)
  - 1933, 295356 (Box 10)
  - 1934, 295357 (Box 10)
  - 1935 I, 295358 (Box 11)
  - 1935 II, 295359 (Box 11)
  - 1936, 295360 (Box 11)
  - 1937 I, 295361 (Box 11)
  - 1937 II, 295362 (Box 11)
  - 1938, 295363 (Box 11)
  - 1939 I, 295371 (Box 11)
  - 1939 II, 295372 (Box 11)
  - 1940, 295373 (Box 11)
  - 1941, 295374 (Box 11)
  - 1943-1946, 295375 (Box 11)
  - 1947, 295376 (Box 11)
  - 1948-1949, 295377 (Box 11)
  - 1950-1952, 295378 (Box 11)
  - 1953-1954, 295379 (Box 11)
  - 1955-1959, 295380 (Box 11)
  - 1960, 295381 (Box 11)
  - 1961, 295382 (Box 11)
  - 1962, 295383 (Box 11)
  - 1963, 295384 (Box 11)
  - 1964, 295385 (Box 11)
  - 1965-1966, 295386 (Box 11)
  - 1967, 295388 (Box 11)
  - 1968-1969, 295389 (Box 11)
  - 1970, 295390 (Box 11)
  - 1971-1975, 2002, 295391 (Box 12)
  - Undated I, 295392 (Box 12)
  - Undated II, 295393 (Box 12)
  - Undated III, 295394 (Box 12)
  - Undated IV, 295395 (Box 12)
  - Undated V, 295396 (Box 12)
  - Undated VI, 295397 (Box 12)
  - Undated VII, 295398 (Box 12)
  - Undated VII, 295399 (Box 12)
  - Chicago (IL), undated; 295403 (Box 12)
  - Education Committee, undated; 346682 (Box 12)
  - Fourth Internationalists, 1937, undated; 295410 (Box 12)
  - Indiana University, Bloomington (IN), undated; 295404 (Box 12)